Derrick Severin

Kitchener, Canada Area

Walters Group - Plant Supervisor - Princeton Site

Summary

Experienced Supervisor with a demonstrated history of working in the Industry. Skilled in multiple welding processes, Project Estimation, Welding Inspection, Weld Instruction, Welding Equipment Maintenance and Troubleshooting, People Management and Mentoring, Custom Metal Fabrication, Sheet Metal, and Construction. Confident Professional with a Welder-Fitter Certificate focused in Welding Technology/Welder from Cambrian College Sudbury and a CWB Certified Welding Supervisor.

Experience

Supervisor at Walters Inc. Princeton

April 2011 - Present (7 years 9 months)

Welding Supervisor at Becland Stamping and Machining Corporation

May 2010 - April 2011 (1 year)

Attempted to implement and oversee the certification of Becland to CWB Certification W47.1 /W59. However due the down turn in the economy and a struggle with sales; it was the decision of the employers to forfeit the position.

WELDING TECHNOLOGIST at Conestoga College Institute of Technology February 2010 - April 2010 (3 months)

- Instructing and guiding students in the fundamentals of welding technology and safety in the industry
- Instruct, demonstrate, evaluate and guide essential skills for: Oxy Fuel Welding, Braze Welding, Oxy Fuel Cutting, SMAW, GMAW, GTAW and FCAW influencing an array of Trades such as: Welding Techniques, Renovation Techs, Construction Techs Level I and II, Plumber Apprentices Level I and II, Carpentry Apprentices, Millwrights Level I and II, and Motive Power Techs
- Maintain the Weld Shop and equipment in good working order so students may demonstrate skills safely and effectively
- Demonstrate professional level record keeping for all students through the use of spreadsheets, open line communication, discipline and documentation of evaluated skills
- Sustain professional level communication with colleagues by discussing opportunities to improve infrastructure and the means to positively influence how students receive the knowledge and skills learned while participating in Weld Shop activities

- WHMIS and AODA (Accessibility for Ontarians with Disabilities Act) trained
- Control and maintain a streamline inventory for all shop equipment, electrodes, bottled gases and building materials

PLANT MANAGER at RJ Metal Fabrication Inc.

February 2004 - December 2009 (5 years 11 months)

- Returned to RJ to oversee production and maintain CWB certification of W47.1/W59
- Prioritized workflow to meet the demands of our Customers
- Reviewed blueprints and drawings for proper welding symbols and dimensional accuracy and performed job cost estimating, developed jigs and fixtures for prototypes, R&D and production
- Worked with employees guiding them through jobs to ensure quality standards were met through first off inspection of parts.
- When required, worked on the floor as a welder fitter, and CNC Plasma Operator, and operated other machinery to ensure timely delivery of product.
- Worked inside the office prioritizing and preparing orders for the floor and managed ISO
- Efficient with Microsoft Word, Excel and Outlook

PLANT MANAGER/SUPERVISOR at Baumeier Engineered Products Inc

November 2002 - February 2004 (1 year 4 months)

- Established, implemented and maintained CWB certification of W47.1/W59
- Scheduled and prioritized workflow to meet the demands of our Customers
- Reviewed blueprints and drawings for proper welding symbols and dimensional accuracy and when necessary, developed jigs and fixtures for prototype, R&D and production purposes
- Worked with assigned employees guiding them through the jobs to meet quality standards through first off inspections and production reports
- Responsible for the purchase of tools and consumables for all areas of the Plant
- Communicated and reported to the VP of Manufacturing, VP of Finance and the Quality Control Manager in daily meetings to ensure quality, productivity and timely delivery

WELDING SUPERVISOR/CNC MACHINE OPERATOR at RJ Metal Fabrication Inc September 1998 - November 2002 (4 years 3 months)

- Responsible for all CWB business such as audit reports, WPS, WPDS, dimensioning weld symbols on blueprints and maintaining a quality system.
- Excellent management and organization skills; maintaining inventory for the welding and plasma cutting departments
- Involved in the Joint Health and Safety committee and WHMIS trained, was an active member of the ISO 2000 committee for quality control.
- Worked on the floor as a welder fitter. Skilled workmanship in production through the building and use of jigs and fixtures, through such processes as GMAW and GTAW

- Have achieved certification for GMAW and GTAW processes in various positions such as flat, horizontal, and vertical down, through the use of hard wire up to 0.0625 diameter as well as tungsten electrodes up to 0.125 diameter.
- Experienced at welding in all positions.
- Fabricated parts for the structural, automotive, and local industry using various types of raw material through the operation of a CNC, single gantry Plasma Cutter.
- Experienced workmanship with cutting processes such as acetylene torches and hand held plasma cutters. Familiar with fork lift operation, drill presses, lathes, Strippit punch presses, horizontal band saws, press brakes, holding tolerances from +/- 0.015 and +/- 0.5mm

Education

Cambrian College Sudbury
Welder-Fitter Certificate, Welding Technology/Welder, 1997 - 1998

Derrick Severin

Kitchener, Canada Area

Walters Group - Plant Supervisor - Princeton Site



Profile Notes and Activity (2)

12/11/2018—View by Laura Wickware

12/11/2018—InMail sent by Stephen Hime ({1})

Dominic Townsend

Kitchener, Canada Area

Production Supervisor at Hammond Manufacturing Co. Ltd

Summary

The only thing that is constant is change.

Experience

Production Supervisor at Hammond Manufacturing Co. Ltd January 2018 - Present (1 year)

Assembler/Packager, Chroma at Hammond Manufacturing Co. Ltd October 2015 - December 2017 (2 years 3 months)

Maintenance Administrator at Canadian Solar Solutions, Inc.

April 2012 - October 2015 (3 years 7 months)

Order all spare parts and consumables for manufacturing, engineering and maintenance use.

Maintain min./max. levels for spare parts and consumables.

Maintain periodic maintenance tracking.

Reduced yearly spares and consumables costs through alternate vendors and equipment.

Introduce traceability through the elimination of miscellaneous purchases throughout the plant.

Maintain 5S and general maintenance shop cleanliness.

Generate reports based on maintenance, production and engineering spending.

Create and modify maintenance SOP's and WI's

Stable Hand/Maintenance at Leatherstone Equestrian Center

September 2007 - February 2012 (4 years 6 months)

Fed, handled and groomed horses.

Maintained all equipment including golf carts, tractors lawn mowers.

Maintained the facility including electrical, plumbing, carpentry and general grounds maintenance.

Dealt with customers in a one on one environment.

Team Member at Toyota Motor Manufacturing Canada

May 2001 - February 2007 (5 years 10 months)

Maintaining production line inventory levels utilizing FIFO, Kanbans and JIT in a safe manner using both forklifts and tow motors.

Spot weld automobile parts in a timely manner.

Remain mindful of 5S at all times.

Quality Technician at Linamar

April 1996 - April 2001 (5 years 1 month)

As a Quality Technician I was in charge of calibrating tools and equipment used in the assembling and testing of small engines and differential units as well as incoming quality inspections.

I had also held roles as Supervisor at DiversCast a lost foam foundry that Linamar operated for a number of years and in the Engineering Department at LPP trying to eliminate NVH from a differential unit that we were building for GM.

Education

Fairview College

Motorcycle Maintenance and Repair Technology/Technician, 1993 - 1994

Activities and Societies: NumBum '94 team member

Dominic Townsend

Kitchener, Canada Area

Production Supervisor at Hammond Manufacturing Co. Ltd



Profile Notes and Activity (2)

12/11/2018—View by Stephen Hime

12/11/2018—InMail sent by Stephen Hime ({1})

John Legare, RSE

Hamilton, Ontario, Canada

Mechanic, lead hand GFL Hamilton

Summary

Experienced Diesel Technician with a demonstrated history of working in the environmental services industry. Skilled in Operations Management, Heavy Equipment, Inspection, Forklift Operation, and Metal Fabrication. Strong operations professional with a Completion of 310T apprenticeship focused in Medium/Heavy Vehicle and Truck Technology/Technician from Mohawk College.

Experience

Diesel Technician Shop Lead Hand at GFL Environmental Inc.

December 2014 - Present (4 years 1 month)

Maintenance Supervisor at Catholic Youth Organization

September 2014 - Present (4 years 4 months)

Maintenance supervisor at Marydale Park

Welder Fabricator/ Lead hand at Universal Handling Equipment

June 2003 - November 2014 (11 years 6 months)

Fabricated boxes, roll-off hoists, trailers, lugger trucks, front end loaders and single and double stream rear end loaders for waste refuse companies. I also work service and learned electrical and hydraulic functions of the trucks for new installation and maintenance of the equipment.

Welder Fabricator at EDM Tool

2007 - 2013 (6 years)

Custom fabrication of cutting tables for the metal industry.

Education

Bishop Ryan Highschool

Graduated 2000

Mohawk College

Welder Trade Certification 2001

Mohawk College

Completion of 310T apprenticeship , Medium/Heavy Vehicle and Truck Technology/Technician

John Legare, RSE

Hamilton, Ontario, Canada Mechanic, lead hand GFL Hamilton



Profile Notes and Activity (2)

12/11/2018—View by Laura Wickware

12/11/2018—InMail sent by Stephen Hime ({1})